This is the Gate of Destruction.
這是破壞之門。
MUTSUGI.
夢繼法師。
There was a forbidden fruit that granted omniscience and omnipotence to those who ate it.
有一種禁果，吃了它的人會獲得全知全能。
It's inside the gate.
就在大門裡面。
what are you saying?
你在說什麼？
You can get the forbidden fruit.
你可以獲得禁果。
A world without HORROR will be realized.
一個沒有駭魔的世界將會實現。
GODOU, open the Gate of Destruction now.
護道，現在就打開破壞之門吧。
You don't say anything stupid.
你別說些傻話。
You know what will happen when you open the gate.
你知道當你打開大門時會發生什麼。
GODOU, the seal on the Gate of Destruction is broken.
護道，破壞之門的封印被解除了。
What is GODOU planning to do?
護道打算做什麼？
I do the right thing.
我做正確的事。
You will be cursed if you continue like this.
如果再這樣下去，你會被詛咒的。
Even if this body perishes, this gate must not be opened.
縱然此身滅亡，此門也絕不能開啟。
my father.
我的父親。
KEITA AMEMIYA.
雨宮啟太。
TOUHOKUSHINSHYA.
東北神夏。
KIYOTAKA NINOMIYA.
二宮清隆。
GARO：Heir To Steel Armor.
牙狼＜GARO＞鋼之繼承者。
WATARU KURIYAMA.
栗山涉。
ON NAKANO.
在中野。
MIKO NAKAZAWA.
中澤美子。
TOMOKA KUROTANI.
黑谷智香。
MASATO HAGIWARA.
萩原正人。
HIRONOBU KAGEYAMA.
影山博宣。
KENTEZ ASAKA, AKIHIRO YAMAMOTO, SYUN NISHIME.
朝坂肯特斯、山本昭宏、西目俊。
AYA TANAKA, ICHIROU HIGA, SYUUHEI OKABAYASHI.
田中綾、比嘉一郎、岡林修平。
RIUJI YOSHIZAKI, YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
吉崎隆二、木村佳勝。
Opening theme "GARO HAGANE wo Inheritor WITH JAM PROJECT" composed and arranged by YUKI KAJIURA.
片頭主題曲《GARO ①鋼鎧 wo InheritorWITH JAM PROJECT》由梶浦由紀作曲、編曲。
YUNJI INOUE, YOSHICHIKA KURIYAMA, SHIHO TERADA.
井上雲二、栗山芳親、寺田志保。
JUNYA HOSHI, AKIRA NISHIOKA, MINAMISONO TOMOO, NAOKI TAIRA, HIROYASU KOIZUMI, MAYUMI KOMORI, SHIGEYUKI NAKAGAWA, TSUYOSHI KADUNO.
星淳也、西岡晃、南園友尾、平直樹、小泉弘安、小森真由美、中川重行、角野剛之。
YOU-KO, NOBORU KAWAKAMI, AKITERU NAKADA, JIRO.
陽子、川上升、中田昭輝、二郎。
MASAKI SUZUMURA.
鈴村正樹。
YOSHIKATSU KIMURA.
木村芳勝。
What did you do to SOUMA?
你對創磨做了什麼？
SOUMA.
創磨。
I take on armor to protect the world.
我穿上鎧甲來保護世界。
Deception.
困惑。
SOUMA.
創磨。
RYUGA, don't get in my way.
流牙，別妨礙我。
you.
你。
I have no grudge against RYUGA.
我與流牙並無怨恨。
KOYORI.
來依。
Please, please stop.
拜託，請停下來。
You don't get in the way.
你不會妨礙。
Your opponent is me.
你的對手是我。
SOUMA.
創磨。
What did you come for?
你來幹什麼？
what?
什麼？
I have no use for you.
我對你沒有任何用處。
It hurts here.
這裡疼。
After all, you are just like us.
畢竟，你和我們一樣。
You're also just a HAGANE, right?
你也只是①鋼鎧吧？
What do you know?
你知道什麼？
SOUMA, please show me more of your Grudge.
創磨，請給我展示更多你的陰我。
SOUMA.
創磨。
KOYORI.
來依。
There's no way SOUMA can surpass GODOU.
創磨不可能超越護道。
In the first place, SOUMA cannot even catch up with GODOU.
本來，創磨護道都追不上。
You don't fool around.
你別胡鬧。
Don't be SOUMA by that.
別被這創磨了。
GODOU.
護道。
RYUGA, my son is GARO.
流牙，我的兒子是牙狼。
what?
什麼？
That means hope, right?
這意味著希望，對嗎？
Hope.
希望。
Yes, that's hope.
是的，這就是希望。
I won't let your hope die here.
我不會讓你的希望在這裡破滅。
How long are you going to defy me?
你還要反抗我到什麼時候？
That is until you return to the original MUTSUGI.
直到你回到原來的夢繼法師。
I believed that KOYORI would understand.
我相信來依會理解的。
It's coming soon.
很快就來了。
You responded well.
你反應很好。
Don't look down on me.
別小看我。
That's true.
這是真的。
You were my disciple.
你是我的弟子。
I have come this far because of you.
因為你，我才走到這一步。
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
I know your kindness and love for people more than anyone else, and your dedication to helping others.
我比任何人都更了解您對人的善良和愛心，以及您樂於助人的奉獻精神。
Why then do you try to open the Gate of Destruction?
那麼為什麼要嘗試打開破壞之門呢？
makai order like us exist to protect people from HORROR.
像我們這樣的守護者的存在是為了保護人們免受駭魔。
I have always believed that it means peace.
我一直相信，這意味著和平。
But what about the reality?
但現實又如何呢？
Exterminating the HORROR will not lead to true peace.
消滅駭魔不會帶來真正的和平。
There are people with bad hearts who are not yet possessed by HORROR.
有些心地不好的人還沒有被駭魔佔據。
Because these people commit crimes, there is no end to the victims.
因為這些人犯罪，受害者無窮無盡。
We should look to the future and eradicate such people.
我們應該放眼未來，消滅這樣的人。
Doing that won't solve anything.
這樣做並不能解決任何問題。
Isn't it our mission as makai order to believe in humans and fight?
相信人類並戰鬥不就是我們身為守護者的使命嗎？
That's crazy.
太瘋狂了。
my father.
我的父親。
what?
什麼？
That's what I thought.
我也這麼想。
Do you think you are strong with that level of strength?
你認為你的實力強到這個程度嗎？
Please don't think that I will always be the same.
請不要以為我會永遠一樣。
You don't get emotional.
你不會情緒化。
You haven't changed in this way.
你並沒有這樣改變。
If you misunderstand GODOU and me, then you should fight me.
如果你誤會了護道和我，那就應該和我戰鬥。
You overcome the darkness.
你戰勝了黑暗。
are you in pain?
你很痛苦嗎？
The answer lies ahead.
答案就在前方。
MUTSUGI.
夢繼法師。
you are wrong.
您錯了。
GARO.
牙狼。
HAGANE.
①鋼鎧。
MUTSUGI.
夢繼法師。
you are wrong.
您錯了。
This is already good, right?
這已經很好了，對吧？
I don't need to continue this futile battle with you any longer.
我不需要再和你繼續這場徒勞的戰鬥了。
SOUMA.
創磨。
MUTSUGI is right.
夢繼法師說得對。
Please follow what MUTSUGI says.
請照夢繼法師所說的去做。
Is MUTSUGI correct?
夢繼法師正確嗎？
The answer you seek lies within that suffering.
你所尋求的答案就在痛苦之中。
You overcome the darkness.
你戰勝了黑暗。
I am a makai order.
我是守護者。
I don't care if it costs me my life.
我不在乎這是否會讓我付出生命的代價。
I won't do what you want now.
我現在不會做你想做的事。
You overcome the darkness.
你戰勝了黑暗。
The only thing you have to overcome is yourself.
你唯一需要克服的就是你自己。
SOUMA, what you have to overcome is yourself.
創磨，你要克服的是你自己。
Be strong in your heart.
內心要堅強。
SOUMA please come back.
創磨請回來吧。
You overcome the darkness.
你戰勝了黑暗。
You are HAGANE.
你是①鋼鎧。
Together with me, you can change this world.
和我一起，你可以改變這個世界。
I refuse it.
我拒絕。
Is that so?
是這樣嗎？
It seems you didn't understand what I said.
看來你沒明白我說的話。
Your actions end there.
你的行動到此結束。
SOUMA.
創磨。
I overcame the darkness.
我戰勝了黑暗。
A wandering heart that struggles alone will melt into an AMBITIOUS city.
一顆獨自奮鬥的漂泊之心，將融入一座雄心勃勃的城市。
The soul breaks and scatters.
靈魂破碎、四散。
As the moonlight laughs, he says he can't save her and opens the gate.
月代笑著說他救不了她並打開了門。
The sky is blurring white now.
天空現在已經變成了模糊的白色。
Wings soar through the darkness.
翅膀在黑暗中翱翔。
BREAK THROUGH You can soar.
突破 你可以翱翔。
It is a SWORD DANCE of darkness and light.
這是黑暗與光明的劍舞。
SIN MY FAITH until the day the evil desires disappear.
違背我的信仰，直到邪惡慾望消失的那一天。
This story is a fiction.
這個故事是虛構的。
This story has nothing to do with any real people, organizations, or incidents.
本故事與任何真實的人物、組織或事件無關。
The Gate of Destruction will return to its original form.
破壞之門恢復原來的樣子。
This is his aim.
這就是他的目標。
The world you seek is not a utopia.
你所尋求的世界不是烏托邦。
Temptation.
誘惑。